Jan Karon papers MSS 16077
University of Virginia, Special Collections Dept.
- Esmont Architectural Drawings and Papers
  - Architectural Drawings, chiefly of Esmont
    - Jan Karon Residence, Desk, Michael Galleher, Valle, Crucis, North Carolina, 1 oversize sheet, 1998; 1 folder(s) (Oversize folder flat file 14)
    - Esmont - Architectural Drawings – Interior Elevations, 1 oversize sheet, DEPG, 2001; 1 folder(s) (Oversize folder flat file 14)
    - Esmont - Architectural Drawings – Main Gate Elevations and Details, 4 oversize sheets, DEPG, 2002; 1 folder(s) (Oversize folder flat file 14)
    - Esmont - Architectural Drawings – Kitchen Porch, 1 oversize sheet, DEPG, 2005; 1 folder(s) (Oversize folder flat file 14)
    - Esmont - Architectural Drawings – Garden Porch Furnishings, 1 oversize sheet, DEPG, 2005; 1 folder(s) (Oversize folder flat file 14)
    - Esmont – Architectural Drawings – Interior Woodworking, Gaston & Wyatt, Inc. Fine Woodworking, 8 oversize sheets, 2000-2002; 1 folder(s) (Oversize folder flat file 15)
    - Esmont – Architectural Drawings – Planting Plans and Entrance Drive Tree Planting Plans, Rachel M. Lilly, Landscape Architect, 13 oversize sheets, 2000-2003; 1 folder(s) (Oversize folder flat file 16)
    - Esmont – Architectural Drawings – Schedule of Drawings – DEPG, 23 oversize sheets, 2001 May-June; 1 folder(s) (Oversize box 2, Oversizefolder 1)
    - Esmont – Architectural Drawings – Schedule of Drawings – DEPG, 33 oversize sheets, 2001 May-July; 1 folder(s) (Oversize box 2, Oversizefolder 2)
    - Esmont – Architectural Drawings – Schedule of Drawings – DEPG, 40 oversize sheets, 2001-2002; 1 folder(s) (Oversize box 2, Oversizefolder 3)
    - Esmont – Architectural Drawings – Schedule of Drawings – DEPG, 40 oversize sheets, 2001-2002; 1 folder(s) (Oversize box 2, Oversizefolder 4)
    - Esmont – Architectural Drawings – Schedule of Drawings – DEPG, 46 oversize sheets, 2001-2002; 1 folder(s) (Oversize box 2, Oversizefolder 5)
    - Esmont – Architectural Drawings – Interior and Garage Elevations; Kitchen Elevations; Electrical Plans; Garage Foundation Plan; Exterior Front and Back, 15 oversize sheets, 2001-2002, undated; 1 folder(s) (Oversize box 2, Oversizefolder 6)
    - Esmont – Architectural Drawings – Kitchen, Study and Pantry Elevations, 12 oversize sheets, 2001 May; 1 folder(s) (Oversize box 2, Oversizefolder 7)
    - Esmont – Architectural Drawings – Master Bath, Upstairs Bath and Powder Room; and Floor Plans, 16 oversize sheets, 2000-2001 June; 1 folder(s) (Oversize box 2, Oversizefolder 8)
    - Esmont – Architectural Drawings – Elevations; Topographical Study; and Site Plan, 32 oversize sheets, 2000 May-June; 1 folder(s) (Oversize box 2, Oversizefolder 9)
    - Esmont – Architectural Drawings – Front Entry Site Plan and Front Gate, 11 oversize sheets, 2002; 1 folder(s) (Oversize box 2, Oversizefolder 10)
    - Jan Karon Residence – Plans for a Studio, Blowing Rock, North Carolina, by Dennis J. Lehmann, 6 oversize sheets, 1997; 1 folder(s) (Oversize box 3, Oversizefolder 10)
    - Esmont – Architectural Drawings – Chapel drawings by JWS Joinery Fine Carpentry and Furnishings, Floor Plans and Elevations, Roof Details, Conceptual Plan and Revisions, 19 oversize sheets, 2007; 1 folder(s) (Oversize box 3, Oversizefolder 11)
    - Esmont – Architectural Drawings – Chapel drawings by JWS Joinery Fine Carpentry and Furnishings, Doors and Windows, Lattice Work, 10 oversize sheets, 2007-2008; 1 folder(s) (Oversize box 3, Oversizefolder 12)
  - Esmont Papers
    - Esmont, 1997-2001; 1 folder(s) (Box 101, Folder 1)
    - Esmont, undated; 1 folder(s) (Box 101, Folder 2)
    - Esmont – Architectural drawings and sketches of the picket fence, front gate, post tops, chapel and garage, 2002-2004; 1 folder(s) (Box 101, Folder 3)
    - Esmont – Building Analysis Report, 1999 August; 1 folder(s) (Box 101, Folder 4)
    - Esmont – Celebration and Blessing of a New Home, 1999 November 3; 1 folder(s) (Box 101, Folder 5)
    - Esmont - Chapel, 2000-2012; 1 folder(s) (Box 101, Folder 6)
    - Esmont – Dalgliesh, Eichman, Gilpin & Paxton, Architects (3 folders), 1999-2008; 3 folder(s) (Box 101)
    - Esmont – Entertaining, 2002-2004; 1 folder(s) (Box 101, Folder 10)
    - Esmont – Entertaining – Birthday Tea for Wanda Setzer and Children’s Party, 2005 April-May; 1 folder(s) (Box 102, Folder 1)
    - Esmont – Entertaining – Dinner on the Porch for Patrick and Arlette de Barros, 2005 June 10; 1 folder(s) (Box 102, Folder 2)
    - Esmont – Entertaining – Wedding of Jennifer Leigh Craig and Michael David Gray, 2005 September 17; 1 folder(s) (Box 102, Folder 3)
    - Esmont – Entertaining – White Tea, article in September-October, 2006 issue of "Tea Time", 2006 June 17; 1 folder(s) (Box 102, Folder 4)
    - Esmont – Entertaining – White Tea, choices and samples, 2006 June 17; 1 folder(s) (Box 102, Folder 5)
    - Esmont – Entertaining – White Tea, correspondence with Millie Travis, Events with Style, 2005-2006, 2006 June 17; 1 folder(s) (Box 102, Folder 6)
    - Esmont – Entertaining – White Tea, correspondence, 2006 March-April; 1 folder(s) (Box 102, Folder 7)
    - Esmont – Entertaining – White Tea, correspondence, 2006 May-June; 1 folder(s) (Box 102, Folder 8)
    - Esmont – Entertaining – White Tea, guest information, 2006 June 17; 1 folder(s) (Box 102, Folder 9)
    - Esmont – Entertaining – White Tea, photographs, 2006 June 17; 1 folder(s) (Box 102, Folder 10)
    - Esmont – Entertaining – White Tea, planning and arrangements, 2006 June 17; 1 folder(s) (Box 103, Folder 1)
    - Esmont – Entertaining – White Tea, thank you notes (3 folders), 2006 June-September; 3 folder(s) (Box 103)
    - Esmont – Entertaining, 2006-2007; 1 folder(s) (Box 103, Folder 5)
    - Esmont – Entertaining – Bridal Tea, 2007 May 12; 1 folder(s) (Box 103, Folder 6)
    - Esmont – Entertaining – Bridal Tea, thank you notes, 2007 May 12; 1 folder(s) (Box 103, Folder 7)
    - Esmont- Entertaining – “A Mitford Sunday Picnic” to benefit St. Stephen’s Church Building Fund (Canceled), 2007 October 7; 1 folder(s) (Box 103, Folder 8)
    - Esmont – Entertaining – Tea, 2007 October 21; 1 folder(s) (Box 103, Folder 9)
    - Esmont – Entertaining – Musical Evening, 2007 November 16; 1 folder(s) (Box 103, Folder 10)
    - Esmont – Entertaining – Monticello Cabinet Luncheon (1 of 2 folders), 2008 June 14; 1 folder(s) (Box 103, Folder 11)
    - Esmont – Entertaining – Monticello Cabinet Luncheon (2 of 2 folders), 2008 June 14; 1 folder(s) (Box 104, Folder 1)
    - Esmont – Entertaining – House Party, 2008 September 22; 1 folder(s) (Box 104, Folder 2)
    - Esmont – Entertaining – Thanksgiving, 2008; 1 folder(s) (Box 104, Folder 3)
    - Esmont – Entertaining, 2009-2012; 1 folder(s) (Box 104, Folder 4)
    - Esmont – Entertaining – Wedding celebration dinner for Lee Manning and Neal Kassell, 2011 June 17; 1 folder(s) (Box 104, Folder 5)
    - Esmont – Entertaining – Party for Donna and Albert Ernest, 2012 June 30; 1 folder(s) (Box 104, Folder 6)
    - Esmont – Entertaining – Hospice Event, 2012 September; 1 folder(s) (Box 104, Folder 7)
    - Esmont – Entertaining – Monticello Event, including a scavenger hunt, 2012 October 15; 1 folder(s) (Box 104, Folder 8)
    - Esmont – Entertaining – Dinner Party, 2012 December 20; 1 folder(s) (Box 104, Folder 9)
    - Esmont – Environmental Site Inspection, 1999 August 9; 1 folder(s) (Box 105, Folder 1)
    - Esmont – Families associated with Esmont to 1848 – research, chiefly copies (3 folders), circa 2001-2010; 3 folder(s) (Box 105)
    - Esmont – Families associated with Esmont from 1849 to present - research, chiefly copies (3 folders), circa 2001-2010; 3 folder(s) (Box 105)
    - Esmont – Families associated with Esmont from 1849 to present, research, chiefly copies (4 of 4 folders), circa 2001-2010; 1 folder(s) (Box 106, Folder 1)
    - Esmont – Farm Cottage, 2000; 1 folder(s) (Box 106, Folder 2)
    - Esmont – Farm Office, 2000-2002; 1 folder(s) (Box 106, Folder 3)
    - Esmont – Farm Resources notebook kept by Jan Karon while sole manager of Esmont (2 folders), 2010-2014; 2 folder(s) (Box 106)
    - Esmont – Field Reports and Minutes of the Architects (2 folders), 2000-2003; 2 folder(s) (Box 106)
    - Esmont – Frank Hardy, Inc. Realtors, 1999-2014; 1 folder(s) (Box 106, Folder 8)
    - Esmont – Guest House, 1999-2001; 1 folder(s) (Box 106, Folder 9)
    - Esmont – Historical Marker, 2005-2008; 1 folder(s) (Box 106, Folder 10)
    - Esmont – History (2 folders), 1992-2008; 2 folder(s) (Box 107)
    - Esmont – House Museum, 2003-2004; 1 folder(s) (Box 107, Folder 3)
    - Esmont – House photographic shoot, 2006; 1 folder(s) (Box 107, Folder 4)
    - Esmont – Landscaping Ideas (2 folders), 1999-2015; 2 folder(s) (Box 107)
    - Esmont – Legal and Financial documents, including appraisal, deed (2 folders), 1999-2008, 2014; 2 folder(s) (Box 107)
    - Esmont – Main House, 2000-2001; 1 folder(s) (Box 107, Folder 9)
    - Esmont – Main House (3 folders), 2002-2008, undated; 3 folder(s) (Box 108)
    - Esmont – Main House Estimates, 2001-2003; 1 folder(s) (Box 108, Folder 4)
    - Esmont – Meadowgate Farm, L.L.C., 2003-2005; 1 folder(s) (Box 108, Folder 5)
    - Esmont - Miscellaneous, 1999-2012; 1 folder(s) (Box 108, Folder 6)
    - Esmont – Neighboring Properties, 1996-2005; 1 folder(s) (Box 108, Folder 7)
    - Esmont – Outbuildings, including dairy, machine shed, and barns, 2000-2002; 1 folder(s) (Box 108, Folder 8)
    - Esmont – Photographs of Restoration Work, circa 2000-2003; 1 folder(s) (Box 108, Folder 9)
    - Esmont – Planning and Resource Notebook, 1998-1999; 1 folder(s) (Box 108, Folder 10)
    - Esmont – Research notebook of primary sources, copies only (1 of 2 folders), circa 1968-2004; 1 folder(s) (Box 108, Folder 11)
    - Esmont – Research notebook of primary sources, copies only (2 of 2 folders), circa 1968-2004; 1 folder(s) (Box 109, Folder 1)
    - Esmont - Research notebook of secondary sources (3 folders), 1913, 1999-2010; 3 folder(s) (Box 109)
    - Esmont - Research notebook of secondary sources, Part II, including original Kelley Graham documents and copies of correspondence concerning the remodeling in 1954 by Floyd Johnson, 1953-1954, 2014; 1 folder(s) (Box 109, Folder 5)
    - Esmont – Restoration Tax Credits, 2001-2008; 1 folder(s) (Box 109, Folder 6)
    - Esmont – Samples for an Area Rug and Italian Dining Chairs, 2013; 1 folder(s) (Box 109, Folder 7)
    - Esmont – Shelter Associates, Ltd., 2000; 1 folder(s) (Box 109, Folder 8)
    - Esmont – Shelter Associates, Ltd. (6 folders), 2001-2002 May; 6 folder(s) (Box 110)
    - Esmont – Shelter Associates, Ltd. (7 folders), 2002 July-2003 August; 7 folder(s) (Box 111)
    - Esmont – Shelter Associates, Ltd., 2003 September-December; 1 folder(s) (Box 112, Folder 1)
    - Esmont – Veterinary Services, 2001-2013; 1 folder(s) (Box 112, Folder 2)
    - Esmont – Volume -Farm Journal (6 volumes), 2001-2002, 2007-2010; 6 Volumes (Box 112, Volume 1-6)
    - Esmont – Volume -Farm Journal Inserts, 2003, 2008-2009; 1 folder(s) (Box 112, Folder 3)
    - Esmont – Volume –Photograph Album of Restoration Work (2 volumes), circa 2000-2003; 2 Volumes (Box 113, Volume 1-2)
    - Esmont – Volume –Register of Workers who restored Esmont Farm in Albemarle County, Virginia, 2000-2007, 1 Volumes (Box 113, Volume 3)
    - Esmont – Wallpaper, 2003-2005; 1 folder(s) (Box 113, Folder 1)
    - Esmont – William Gordon Diaries facsimile, correspondence concerning, 2007-2008; 1 folder(s) (Box 113, Folder 2)
    - Esmont – Williamsburg Antiques Forum – The Green Mountain Tour, Albemarle County, Virginia, 2005; 1 folder(s) (Box 113, Folder 3)
- Memorabilia, Artifacts & Miscellany
  - Artifacts, chiefly concerning the Second International Mitford Homecoming
    - Yellow T-Shirt with the quotation “Love is an endless act of forgiveness” for the Fifth International Mitford Homecoming, 2014 September; 1 items (Box 114)
    - 2 Green T-Shirts with the quotation “Draw Close. Hold Hands. Life is Short. God is Good.” by Jan Karon for the Second International Mitford Homecoming, 2007 September 13-16; 1 items (Box 114)
    - Purple T-Shirt with the quotation “Future Inductee National Women’s Hall of Fame, Seneca Falls, New York, undated; 1 items (Box 114)
    - White T-Shirt with the quotation “Mitford Days in Blowing Rock A Festival Celebrating Jan Karon’s Mitford Books”, [2007]; 1 items (Box 114)
    - 3 Cloth Tissue Holders with the quotation “Mitford Days in Blowing Rock A Festival Celebrating Jan Karon’s Mitford Books” designed and made by Linda Whetton, 2007; 1 items (Box 114)
    - Name Badge for Jan Karon for the Second International Mitford Homecoming, [2007]; 1 items (Box 114)
    - Refrigerator Magnet with the quotation “Mitford Days in Blowing Rock A Festival Celebrating Jan Karon’s Mitford Books”, [2007]; 1 items (Box 114)
    - Small Black Travel Utility Bag with “Phil. 4:13 For Pete’s Sake! HC2 – Blowing Rock, NC September 2007” on the front of the bag, 2007 September; 1 items (Box 115)
    - Milk Duds box, with “A Mitford Memorable Moment” from Chapter 21 of "At Home in Mitford" attached, given away as part of the [2nd] Annual Mitford Homecoming celebration, [2007]; 1 items (Box 115)
    - Plaque with photograph attached of “Jan Karon, Judge 1997 Gingerbread House Competition The Grove Park Inn Resort”, 1 items (Box 115)
    - Lavender sachet from sales brochure for "Violet Comes to Stay", [2006]; 1 items (Box 115)
    - Crucifix, undated; 1 items (Box 115)
    - pin commemorating the Lewis & Clark Bicentennial at Monticello, 2003; 1 items (Box 115)
    - Ceramic cross fired by the Raku process at the Butterfly Creek Pottery, 2007; 1 items (Box 115)
    - 4 Artifacts found during the restoration of Esmont, 1999-2004, including a large nail, undated; 1 items (Box 115)
    - Crocheted Bookmark with a cross pattern and the scripture Proverbs 16.3, undated; 1 items (Box 115)
    - Ladies gloves belonging to Fannie Belle Bush Cloer (1893-1993), with notes by Jan Karon, dated October 19, 2014 (6 pairs), 2014, undated; 1 items (Box 116)
      Accompanied by notes from Jan Karon, dated October 19, 2014, “These gloves were worn often by my grandmother, Miss Fannie, about whom I wrote the children’s book Miss Fannie’s Hat. Always wearing a smart hat and gloves, she was a faithful Methodist church-goer. She was also a faithful Democrat, though no hat was required.”
  - Albums and Volumes
    - "Book of Common Prayer" given to Jan Karon by Kathy Fallows, Jan notes “My first prayer book as an Episcopalian, Blowing Rock, North Carolina”, 1990; 1 items (Box 117)
    - Journal labeled “J” celebrating Jan Karon with words beginning with or containing the letter J from Emmy [?], 2010 June 10; 1 Volumes (Box 117)
    - Photograph Album (flower cover) commemorating the visit of Jan Karon to Holly Springs, Mississippi on February 16, 2006 and presented by Mary Ruth Minor to Jan Karon on her return visit to Holly Springs and the signing of "Home to Holly Springs", 2007 October 30; 1 album (Box 117)
    - Photograph Album (green) celebrating the visit of Jan Karon to Once Upon a Time bookstore, Montrose, California, and the meeting of the Mitford Appreciation Society, includes some clippings, [1997] April 19; 1 album (Box 117)
    - Tribute Album (cloth white cover) from Charlotte Dark, fan and mother of nine, includes photographs of her family, recipes, and Christmas greeting cards, undated; 1 album (Box 117)
    - Handmade Album of envelopes which contain letters from members of the Jan Karon online bulletin board who also contributed squares for a quilt honoring Jan Karon and has a Victor Hugo quotation on the front, 2002-2005; 1 Volumes (Box 117)
    - Presentation Book containing book plates commemorating the National Book Festival Gala at the Library of Congress, 2001 September 7; 1 Volumes (Box 117)
    - Daily Prayer Journal, 1987; 1 Volumes (Box 117)
    - Memoranda Book with Barn and Sheep on the cover, includes some dialogue and notes for Jan Karon’s books, undated; 1 Volumes (Box 117)
  - Books Influential in the Life of Jan Karon
    - "The Jolly Jump-Ups Favorite Nursery Stories," a favorite book from childhood, 1942; 1 Volumes (Box 118)
    - "The Pocket Book of Robert Frost’s Poems" with an introduction and commentary by Louis Untermeyer, given to Jan Karon by her grandmother at Christmas 1946, “this book had a powerful influence on my inner life and zeal to become an author” note dated January 22, 1999, 1 Volumes (Box 118)
    - "The Creative Process" edited by Brewster Ghiselin, with the note “An important work, read many times over when I was in my twenties and thirties”, 1955; 1 Volumes (Box 118)
    - "A Pocket Book of Modern Verse An Anthology" edited by Oscar Williams and "Great Essays" edited by Houston Peterson, with the note “books which were extremely meaningful to my life as a young woman,” dated January 22, 1999, 1958, 1960; 2 Volumes (Box 118)
    - "Response 5," Volume 2, Number 1, Jan founded and edited this quarterly publication as Jan Orth, Charlotte, North Carolina, for several issues, 1962; 1 Volumes (Box 118)
    - "A Light in the Window" by Mary Roberts Rinehart, with the note “after publishing the Mitford novel "A Light in the Window" in 1997, Jan learned that M.R. Rinehart had used this title in 1922, 1992; 1 Volumes (Box 118)
  - Audiovisual and Born Digital Material
    - “Garrison’s”, 1981 May; 1 Cassettes (Othertype Audiocassette 3605)
    - "Today Show" congratulations on Jan Karon’s answering machine, 1996 November 3; 1 Cassettes (Othertype Audiocassette 3606)
    - ITT’s Salute to the Arts, “Mitford Chronicles”, 1997 November 26; 1 Cassettes (Othertype Audiocassette 3607)
    - North Carolina Author’s Series Radio interview of Jan Karon, Author’s copy, 1997; 1 Cassettes (Othertype Audiocassette 3608)
    - Interview with Jan Karon on “The Fine Print,” WPLN, Nashville, Tennessee, 1998 February 21 and 22; 1 Cassettes (Othertype Audiocassette 3609)
    - Mitford Appreciation Society, Thanksgiving Messages, 1998 November 17; 1 Cassettes (Othertype Audiocassette 3610)
    - Christmas greetings to Jan Karon from Leah Morgan, Sharpsburg, Maryland, 1998; 1 Cassettes (Othertype Audiocassette 3611)
    - Jan Karon and a Day in Mitford, Trinity Presbyterian Church, Montgomery, Alabama, 1999 April 20; 1 Cassettes (Othertype Audiocassette 3612)
    - Interview with S.J. Boatwright concerning Esmont and Esmont Farm history, 2000 April 5; 1 Cassettes (Othertype Audiocassette 3613)
    - "A Common Life," music selections for the audiobook sent for Jan Karon’s approval, [2000 August]; 1 Cassettes (Othertype Audiocassette 3614)
    - Master Tape for Jan Karon, Jacksonville, Florida, 2002 February; 1 Cassettes (Othertype Audiocassette 3615)
    - Untitled, with note “12-7, 10-74”, undated; 1 Cassettes (Othertype Audiocassette 3616)
    - Birthday song for Mom [Jan Karon] from her daughter, Candace Freeland, undated; 1 Cassettes (Othertype Audiocassette 3617)
    - Unknown correspondent, “Letter to Jan Karon”, undated; 1 Cassettes (Othertype Audiocassette 3618)
    - Christmas messages on answering machine, including one from Candace Freeland, undated; 1 Cassettes (Othertype Audiocassette 3619)
    - Wilson family history, undated; 1 Cassettes (Othertype Audiocassette 3620)
    - Untitled, undated; 1 Cassettes (Othertype Audiocassette 3621)
  - Mitford computer game based on the computer game Mahjong, developed by Jamie D. Wilson, Zebulon, North Carolina and sent with a letter, February 17, 1998, to Jan Karon, 1 items 3.5 floppy disk (Othertype Disk 2473-000)
  - Archival copy of all hard drive contents, Gateway, [backup disk], 2001 November 19-2002 February 24; 1 items 250 MB iomega zip drive (Othertype Disk 2474-000)
  - All contents of Gateway system, [backup disk], 2002 April 17-August 9; 1 items 250MB iomega zip drive (Othertype Disk 2475-000)
  - "Jan Karon’s Mitford Cookbook and Kitchen Reader," manuscript disk returned October 2002 by N. Nicholas, 2002 August; 1 items 3.5 floppy disk (Othertype Disk 2476-001)
  - "Jan Karon’s Mitford Cookbook and Kitchen Reader," manuscript disk returned October 2002 by N. Nicholas, 2002 August; 1 items 3.5 floppy disk (Othertype Disk 2476-002)
  - "Jan Karon’s Mitford Cookbook and Kitchen Reader," manuscript disk returned October 2002 by N. Nicholas, 2002 August; 1 items 3.5 floppy disk (Othertype Disk 2476-003)
  - ["In This Mountain"], 2002 August 30; 1 items 3.5 floppy disk (Othertype Disk 2477-000)
  - “At Home in Mitford” Focus on the Family Radio Theatre, Episode 3, incomplete set, 2003 January 18-19; 1 items compact disk (Othertype Disk 2478-001)
  - “At Home in Mitford” Focus on the Family Radio Theatre, Episode 4, incomplete set, 2003 January 25-26; 1 items compact disk (Othertype Disk 2478-002)
  - “At Home in Mitford” Focus on the Family Radio Theatre, Episode 5, incomplete set, 2003 February 1-2; 1 items compact disk (Othertype Disk 2478-003)
  - “At Home in Mitford” Focus on the Family Radio Theatre, Episode 6, incomplete set, 2003 February 8-9; 1 items compact disk (Othertype Disk 2478-004)
  - Backup disk from laptop, “Jan’s old stuff”, 2004 March 15; 1 items 250 MB iomega zip drive (Othertype Disk 2479-000)
  - “The Jan Karon Story Hour,” 1 of 2 audio compact disks, 2004 July 2; 1 items audio compact disk, total time 67:06 minutes (Othertype Disk 2480-001)
  - “The Jan Karon Story Hour,” 2 of 2 audio compact disks, 2004 July 2; 1 items (Othertype Disk 2480-002)
  - [Backup disk], 2004 September 22, 2004 October 25, and 2005 March 3; 1 items 250MB iomega zip drive (Othertype Disk 2481-000)
  - Public Appearances "Light from Heaven Fall tour," power point of Chapel on the Hill Book Teas – Mitford, 2005 November 8; 1 items CD-R 700 MB (Othertype Disk 2482-000)
  - Holly Springs research trip photographs, 2006 February; 1 items CD-R (Othertype Disk 2483-000)
  - "Home to Holly Springs" trip photographs, [2006 February?]; 1 items CD-R (Othertype Disk 2484-000)
  - Spier NY Viking "Mitford Bedside Companion" Adverstisement, 2006 October 11; 1 items CD, running time 15 seconds (Othertype Disk 2485-000)
  - Spier NY Penguin "Light from Heaven" (PB) Advertisement, 2006 October 12; 1 items CD, running time 15 seconds (Othertype Disk 2486-000)
  - BOOKMARKS, Winston-Salem’s Festival of Books, 89.3 WBFJ-FM radio interview of Jan Karon, 2006 November 3 (airing on November 6); 1 items CD-R (Othertype Disk 2487-000)
  - BOOKMARKS, Winston-Salem’s Festival of Books, WGHP TV Fox 8 Studios – High Point, North Carolina, interview of Jan Karon, 2006 November 7; 1 items DVD, 4 minutes (Othertype Disk 2488-000)
  - BOOKMARKS, Winston-Salem’s Festival of Books, “A Conversation with Jan Karon,” Centenary United Methodist Church Sanctuary main event, Winston-Salem, North Carolina, 2006 November 7; 1 items DVD, 58 minutes (Othertype Disk 2489-000)
  - "Home to Holly Springs casting CD," 1 of 2 disks, 2007 April 3; 1 items CD-R (Othertype Disk 2490-001)
  - "Home to Holly Springs casting CD," 2 of 2 disks, 2007 April 3; 1 items CD-R (Othertype Disk 2490-002)
  - "Home to Holly Springs compressed archive file, unedited, [2007?]; 1 items CD-R (Othertype Disk 2491-000)
  - "Home to Holly Springs," Spier NY, Viking, TV Advertisement, [2007]; 1 items CD, running time 15 seconds (Othertype Disk 2492-000)
  - Esmont – Aerial Images by Leonard G. Phillips (1 of 2 disks), 2008 April; 1 items CD (Othertype Disk 2493-001)
  - Esmont – Aerial Images by Leonard G. Phillips (2 of 2 disks), 2008 April; 1 items CD (Othertype Disk 2493-002)
  - Esmont House Party photographs (1 of 4 disks), 2008 September 27; 1 items CD (Othertype Disk 2494-001)
  - Esmont House Party photographs (2 of 4 disks), 2008 September 27; 1 items CD (Othertype Disk 2494-002)